We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
Do you remember the first time we met, Kimblee?
It seems our positions are now reversed!
Don't you dare look down on me!
Daydream
Kimblee, you bastard!
Why... Why is Winry here?!
We were just about to capture Scar, but now he's taken her hostage!
Move.
Idiot!
Stop, Crimson Alchemist!
Do you not see Winry in front of you?!
Don't get in my way!
Hold it, Scar!
Sir Kimblee, don't go near the building! It's dangerous!
Withdraw!
There's a blizzard approaching! Hurry!
You're a fantastic actor.
That wasn't an act.
I'm actually furious at myself for being such a coward and having to put up such an act.
Why did you kill my parents?
No matter what I say, it'll be only an excuse.
The fact is I killed the Rockbells.
With this hand...
Girl, you have the right to kill me.
At this rate, you'll die from blood loss.
Winry!
I know.
But I'm sure Mom and Dad would have done the same.
It's a life Mom and Dad saved.
I'm sure there's a meaning to it.
You're saying you'll forgive me?
Don't get the wrong idea! I haven't forgiven you for killing my parents unjustly!
Winry...
Don't worry; I'm not going to cry.
Didn't I promise you that the next time I cry, it'd be with tears of joy?
Hey, Scar.
Despite what Winry just said, I still want to beat you to a pulp and drag you over to the Rockbells' graves.
Should I contact Headquarters?
Yeah.
I believe Miles was your name?
Can I ask something?
What is it?
You called me a fellow countryman, didn't you?
I did.
Until my grandfather's generation, my ancestors were full Ishbalans.
I wish we could have met under different circumstances, my red-eyed brethren.
Why are you siding with the Amestrian army?
Because I wish to change the way people feel about Ishbalans from within the country.
I doubt people would change the way they feel so easily.
I don't know how long it'll take.
But there are things only I,
a man of mixed parentage, can do.
I'm nothing but an Ishbalan pebble that was thrown into the Amestrian army.
But there may come a time when
a small ripple becomes a giant wave.
And ironically, the person who made me realize that is a full-blooded Amestrian.
I'm nothing but a mass of hatred, born from that civil war.
I'm glad someone like you exists.
Major.
Is this Headquarters?
This is Miles speaking.
We've captured Scar in a building in Area D.
Let Kimblee know.
No matter what your circumstances are,
I can't just let you go.
You deserve to be tried and sentenced.
Wait!
Who are you?!
May!
Doctor Marcoh!
Please don't take that man away.
This is bad, Sir Kimblee.
The clouds are moving fast.
The weather's about to get pretty ugly.
Then let's hurry.
Deciphering research documents?
It's breakthrough research that combines the alchemies from Amestris and Xing!
But the essential portions are written in ancient Ishbalan.
The only one who can read this is Scar.
So...
You're the girl who knows Eastern Alchemy, right?
I've received orders to take you back to the fort.
Huh?! M-Me?
Don't worry.
I've been ordered to give you a warm reception.
Now... if Scar can't be caught...
...and if we also can't let them know that Marcoh is here...
It might be better to just hide them at Briggs for now.
Hang on, what the hell?!
You're taking him, too?!
Don't you guys need him to decipher the documents?
It pisses me off to think we have to ask him  for help...
Why don't we just hand him over to Kimblee and-
A transmutation circle made from this country.
And the history of this country.
I've heard everything from General Armstrong.
Something is about to happen;
something that will encompass all of Amestris.
Isn't deciphering the documents of higher priority than anything else?
I'm also aware that Ms. Rockbell has been taken hostage.
If we do this now, we could make Kimblee take the blame and hide her away at the same time.
Scar, if you decide to lend us a hand,
we can postpone your trial to a later date.
What do you say?
I have no other options, do I?
I promise to cooperate.
Do you really mean it?
I swear on my Ishbalan blood, my red-eyed brethren.
So, that's how it is.
I'm sorry, but you're going to have to wait a little longer for him to face trial.
That's fine.
Oh yeah, I forgot about these two.
Kill them.
Roger.
H-Hey!
Hang on! You don't have to kill them!
There's nothing to be gained from letting them live.
Do it.
This isn't about gain or loss! Isn't there something you could do besides killing them?!
Showing us pity, huh?
There's no need for that. You're just a kid who doesn't know anything.
There's no future for us anyway, since we've got bodies like these.
If you're going to kill us, just do it.
Don't you two have family or people important to you?
Of course we do.
But when we were transformed to this state, we were publicly pronounced dead.
I haven't seen them since.
Don't you want  to see them?
Even if we did, there's nothing we could do. Look at us.
Oh, so you don't want to return to your old selves?
You're fine with those bodies, then?
Of course not!
Of course we want to return to normal!
Then there's your answer.
Please don't talk as though you've already given up.
You haven't even explored the possibility of returning to your old bodies.
How the hell would you  know how we feel?!
There's no way to-
I'm going to get my body back.
No matter how many years it may take, I'll never give up!
Major!
What is it?
This isn't good.
A blizzard is approaching.
It's impossible to march in a blizzard with the equipment we have right now.
At this rate, we won't make it back to the fort.
What should we do?
Isn't this a mining town?
Why don't we just take the underground mining path?
Wh-What?!
I-It's just that since this is such a big mine, I figured there might be a path leading through the mountain...
I-I think...
That's it!
Sir Yoki!
I used to own a coal mine, after all!
That would work! The mine exits beyond the mountain.
Okay.
If you happen to encounter a soldier from Briggs, hand them this.
I've stated the situation in there, so they should give you refuge.
I'm in your debt.
I guess the only thing we still have to account for is the girl.
Even if she comes with us, wouldn't the Elric Brothers be the prime suspects if they find out she's missing?
We'll figure something out.
Don't mean to brag, but we can work as well as we can talk.
No, Kimblee is a very suspicious man.
If we don't plan this completely, he'll be doubly suspicious.
Umm... this may be a bit strange coming from me...
But...
What if I were kidnapped by Scar?
"Kidnapped"?
So... what you mean is...
We free him, and...
Yeah. Scar runs off with me in his arms, and you pretend like you're desperately trying to stop him...
...or something like that.
Do you think we'll let you do something that dangerous?!
I'm a hostage right now, anyway!
I have to risk my life to escape, or it'll never happen!
But with Scar?!
Yeah! You don't need to risk your  life!
Quit trying to do everything by yourselves! I'm tired of it!
Hurry up and decide. The blizzard is coming.
Pretty soon, we won't even be able to leave this building.
Kimblee's squad is here!
Dammit!
Scar, if anything happens...
I know. I plan to keep my promise.
Could you...
Could you take us, as well?
I understand you don't trust us,
so you can keep us bound.
Sir Kimblee shows no mercy to men who can't do their job.
We'll get killed either way.
And besides...
...we don't want to give up, either!
We can trust you, right?
If you two happen to betray us and get in our way, this country could fall to ruin.
Including the people you two hold dear.
Hang on! What do you mean?!
Central never told us anything like that!
Tell us the details! What is this about?!
Is this fine?
Yeah. You all will probably feel safer this way, too.
Scar, we're going to have to ask you to put on an act.
I know.
Keep the vow you swore on your Ishbalan blood.
Hey! You need to take off your earrings!
Those are made out of metal, aren't they?
If you don't take them off, you'll get frostbite.
Ed.
Hold on to these for me.
I'll be waiting for you at the fort!
Kimblee, you bastard!
Why the hell didn't you keep an eye on Winry?!
I'm worried about Zampano and Jerso.
They were either killed by Scar, or they can't move because of the blizzard...
Scar shouldn't be able to move, either.
He has to be in this town somewhere!
We ought to plan our next search while we're sitting here!
This blizzard really saved us...
I pray that all of you will make it to the fort.
Major Miles, you have a phone call from Briggs.
Miles speaking.
What?!
Oh, so you're the daughter of those Rockbells.
You've heard of my parents?
There isn't a single doctor who was in Ishbal who hasn't.
They fulfilled their duties as doctors without any regard for their own lives.
I haven't forgiven that you killed my parents unjustly!
You must endure.
So you're telling me to forgive the army for what they did?
"Enduring" and "forgiving" are two different things.
You must not forgive the unjustness of society.
As a human being, you must hold the event in contempt.
Yet, you must endure.
You must put an end to the chain of hatred!
If many negative emotions gather,
they will end up influencing the entire world.
But on the other hand, it is also possible to gather positive emotions and lead the world in that direction.
That is why I study alchemy.
Oh, here we are.
What is this place?
It's a post for mine officers.
There should be...
Ah, found it.
See? A detailed map of the mine.
It looks pretty complicated.
I don't understand what goes where.
We can just take this path here, you see?
Wow, you're pretty amazing.
Keep the compliments coming!
With this, we should be able to reach the other side of the mountain a lot faster than we thought we would.
Hey, Doctor Marcoh... Do you think those research documents hold anything to get us back to our old bodies?
There is a possibility.
It's tough to say because it's not a form of alchemy we're familiar with.
I've got faith, Doctor!
I really want to see my family!
Even though your wife was always leading you by the nose?
You probably only want to see your daughter.
Look who's talking! You always turn nasty when you're drunk, so your son was just about fed up with you.
You still have the guts to see him now?
That was brutal.
Is something wrong, May?
No.
I was just wondering when I'll be able to return, since my people are waiting for me...
The philosopher's stone uses the lives of humans.
I mustn't seek such a thing.
Even if I tell him how to create one,
without bringing back an actual stone,
the Emperor would make plans to create one without hesitation.
By sacrificing the lives of many people...
Immortality... Just what should I do?
That answer may also be hidden in those research documents.
So let's try to get to the fort as quickly as we can to decipher them.
You're right.
The fort is no longer safe?!
Major General Armstrong has been summoned to Central.
Many soldiers from Central are now stationed at the fort, as well.
Kimblee must have proposed it.
He was making quite a few phone calls while at the fort, after all.
Hang on. If the Major General is no longer there...
An officer loyal to Bradley is going to be stationed there.
So, Winry and the rest of them...
It's going to be a lot more difficult to hide them there now.
That's hardly the issue. If things take a turn for the worse, they could fall in the hands of the enemy...
We have to let them know somehow!
It would be impossible to go after them in this blizzard.
But we can't just leave them!
I'm going.
An amateur shouldn't take a blizzard lightly!
It'll suck out all your strength in a matter of minutes, leaving you to freeze to death.
There's another option.
There's someone here with a body that knows no fatigue and won't freeze.
This is worse than I expected...
Now, where's the landmark...
There!
I can't see anything with the snow blowing everywhere.
What was that just now? My body?!
Why?
It's impossible to place a soul on a body that doesn't belong.
A body that shouldn't possess a soul...
A rejection reaction!
My old body is pulling my soul towards it!
Come on! Get it together!
I have to hurry.
Alphonse Elric.
Edward Elric.
And...
...Van Hohenheim.
Izumi Curtis is also a possibility.
Just one more.
The promise we never made
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
Koko ni arukara
A departure toward an unknown world.
It's due to one's heart seeking something new.
A human can never go against the wishes of his heart,
but conflict always arises in that moment.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 40, Homunculus.
Homunculus
(The Dwarf in the Flask)
The righteous isn't the one to win.
The one to overcome the boundaries shall stand as the winner.